Prepare for a life of great expectations.
Great Expectations is a drama, romance film directed by Mike Newell.
Orphan Pip discovers through lawyer Mr.
Jaggers that a mysterious benefactor wishes to
ensure that he becomes a gentleman.
Reunited with his childhood patron, Miss Havisham, and his first love, the beautiful but emotionally cold Estella, he discovers that the elderly
spinster has gone mad from having been left at the altar as a young woman, and has made her charge into a warped, unfeeling heartbreaker.
Philip 'Pip' Pirrip, played by Jeremy Irvine.
Miss Havisham, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Abel Magwitch, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Estella Havisham, played by Holliday Grainger.
Mr. Jaggers, played by Robbie Coltrane.
Mrs. Joe, played by Sally Hawkins.
Great Expectations is a 2012 romantic period drama film
based on Charles Dickens' 1861 novel.
The film was directed by Mike Newell and adapted by David Nicholls, and stars Jeremy Irvine,
Helena Bonham Carter, Holliday Grainger, Ralph Fiennes and Robbie Coltrane.
It was distributed by Lionsgate.
Nicholls adapted the screenplay after being asked to work on it by producers Elizabeth Karlsen and
Stephen Woolley, with whom he had worked on And When Did You Last See Your Father?.
Helena Bonham Carter was asked by Newell to appear as Miss Havisham
and accepted the role after some initial
apprehension, while Irvine was initially intimidated by the thought of appearing on screen as Pip.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival.
It was released in the UK on 30 November 2012.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, 19th
century, secret benefactor, young gentleman.
The tone is emotional.